Resume of

Md. Golam Murtaja

Mob: +8801711507022; email: gmurtaja@gmail.com



Career Objective

Passionate individual with 17+ years of market exposure encompassing sales & distribution, customer experience and mobile financial services can be put to use to capitalize opportunities through the power of execution, people development, relationship management and granular analytics to improve the bottom lines and increase company revenue. Love to work with teams and talents to innovate solutions that matter for customers, people, and the society.

Career Summary

Result focused individual with a strong understanding of sales and distribution, customer service, products and offerings especially in telco arena having the ability to work independently and with crossfunctional teams and make critical decisions during challenges. Uncovered many key business drivers and established common ground as identifier of revenue opportunities in different roles over the decades.

Job Experience

Category Head- Enterprise Business

Maxis Systems Ltd. | B2B Collection & Software and Services Startup | Dec 2022 – continued Responsible for

- Identify and develop new business opportunities in terms of new product, clients, markets etc.
- Build relationships with customers, suppliers, distributors, partners, and vendors.
- Lead sales, marketing, customer-service, and client relationship management teams.
- Help to shape the company's long-term objectives and determine plans for how to meet them.
- Evaluate existing partnerships and sales efforts with an eye toward building on what works and changing what doesn't.
- Manage key client relationships in senior level and works to build new ones.
- Expand the profile and reach of the company and its brands.
- Provide advice on product development and distribution and promotion strategies.
- Keep employees focused and motivated, including responsible for hiring, firing and talent development.

Head of Sales & Marketing

VOBON | Building Management Digital Solution in Bangladesh | Jul 2022 – continued Responsible for

- Building the strategic sales model that will effectively cover the company's current and projected markets.
- Working with the AARRR Sales Metrics Diagram (Acquisition Activation Retention Referral Revenue)
- Organize, facilitate and manage all marketing activities and create marketing strategies for the company.
- Expand the relationships with existing customers by continuously proposing solutions that meet their objectives.
- Analyze complex problem cases, as well as develop actions or recommendations to assure sustainable elimination and avoidance.

Major Achievement

- Created and developed all marketing materials for our trade communication that generated an increase in sales of 200 % (QoQ)
- Developed strategic marketing plans that increased our customer base by 30%+ and profits by 50%
- Managed business development opportunities that resulted significant increase in partnerships.

Area Manager

Grameenphone Ltd. | Channel Management | Sales & Distribution | Jul 2017 – Jun 2022

- Managed overall distribution and field force activities for all the channels of the assigned area to ensure optimum availability and trade push of company's products and services at maximum point of sales. (average monthly turnover 300mn)
- Led a team of 7 Territory Managers and their respective staff around 200+ field force.
- Ensured successful execution of sales activities, campaigns in the respective area to meet the area sales and service-related targets.
- Ensured presence and visibility of merchandising materials as per guidelines.
- Provided recommendation on products offering, price points and cluster based campaign design by identifying root cause of issues like product stickiness, customer preference, taker trend analysis etc.
- Led a specialized squad for 1 year consists of experts from different departments within organization to ensure 50% data sub growth.

Professional Achievement:

- Did multiple territory demarcation for efficiency and 9 brand new partner on boarded replacing critical partner and around 8,000 retail outlet expanded on top of existing base (in 5 years)
- Double digit revenue growth delivered in consecutive years (20-21)
- Data sub penetration increased by 60% (YoY: 20 vs. 21)

Circle MFS Head

Grameenphone Ltd. | Channel Development | Sales & Distribution | May 2016 - Jun 2017

- Led a team of 5 Area Managers and their respective staff around 170 employees in field.
- Oversaw distribution management through, efficient cash and liquidity management at all DHs.
- Developed channel coverage model, monitor performance at retail level, drive and initiate necessary campaigns to boost up performance.
- Set strategies in driving business like deposit, withdrawal, billpay, top up, agent creation (acquisition & retention)
- Proactively planned and executed skill development program for FF which was appreciated by the management and rolled out nationally later on.
- Ensured efficient management of targets, KPIs, incentives and initiatives.

Major Achievements/Contribution:

- 17 partner on boarded & 70 skilled field force recruited, trained & deployed in market
- 7.5k MFS Agent on boarded, 100% KYC Compliant & 400k new customer acquisition in a year
- Ensured avg 12k/month utility bill collection and 250mn/month volume transaction (CI&CO)

Revenue Planner and Analyst

Grameenphone Ltd. | Regional Coordination | Product & Campaign Design | Apr 2015 - Apr 2016

- Followed up KPIs and processed post campaign evaluation, monitored BTS utilization and nurtured NPS analytics suggestion for regional consumption and actions.
- Maintained regional performance dashboards across various dimensions, identified gap and improvement areas to facilitate teams in market.
- Ensured liaison between technology and regional sales team to ensure optimum network roll out and investments. (coordinated feasibility study in different projects)
- Identified areas of improvement in network utilization, campaign intake and distribution dimensions and provided feedback to concerned team accordingly.
- Facilitated commercial BI team to set pricing, run different BTL campaign and CLM activities.

Distribution Operations Manager

Grameenphone Ltd. | Distribution House Operation | Territory Business | Jun 2013 - Mar 2015

- Planned and implemented of all sales and RTM activities besides achieving revenue growth.
- Looked after product distribution to ensure optimum product placement at maximum level.
- Followed up KPIs, targets, achievements, and deficits across territory micro level.
- Designed campaign and facilitated analysis for POS expansion to extend distribution reach.
- Developed territory strategy to achieve set target, train DHFF and ensure positive ROI.

Deputy Center Manager

Grameenphone Ltd. | Customer Experience | Flagship Channel Management | Nov 2008 - May 2013

- Facilitated Customer Managers with necessary system insights to develop their performance.
- Ensured successful interaction with "walk in" customers to ensure right customer experience at the shop level.
- Ensured functional and behavioral excellence of frontline agents through right personal development plans, practices, and feedback sessions.
- Managed manpower schedule (roster) to handle regular customer traffic and maintain operational standard.
- Ensure compliance and adherence to customer experience and operational policies and guidelines.

Customer Manager

Grameenphone Ltd. | Customer Experience | After Sales Service | Aug 2005 - Oct 2008

Major duties include providing all sort of after sales service directly to the end user of
Grameenphone. Besides that, involved in various operational activities such as functional reporting,
financial and inventory management.

Assistant Manager

Royal Resort | Corporate Sales and Marketing | Service Development | Feb 2005 - Aug 2005

- Responsible for guide and support sales team with right insight through extensive analysis of revenue, sales, campaigns, and other activities.
- Develop and implementation of sales plan and strategies to lead wide range of marketing team (around 10).
- Maintain business relationship with potential corporate, government and autonomous bodies (lead generation to closing experience).

Marketing Executive

Lighthouse Group | Real Estate | Sales & Marketing | Mar 2004 - Jan 2005

- Maintain relationships with existing customers.
- Build prospect profiles to analyze possible needs and areas of opportunity.
- Set up meetings with potential clients and visit prospective customers regularly.
- Accelerate action plan to identify potential market/clients along with new sales opportunities.

Educational Qualification

MBA in Marketing | 2013 | Northern University Bangladesh
BBA in Business Administration | 2004 | Asian University of Bangladesh
HSC in Science | 1997 | Govt. Azizul Haque College, Bogura
SSC in Science | 1995 | Kahaloo Pilot High School, Bogura

Special Skills

- Strategic thinking and analytics (ability to set goals, directions, milestones etc.)
- Active listener and detail oriented (communicative and affluent in public speaking)
- Maintain strong interpersonal relationship with stakeholders (collaboration and influence)
- Very much familiar with sales, service, systems, and processes

Personal Information

Resident Address : House: 49, Road: 3/F, Sector: 9, Uttara, Dhaka

Date of birth : November 02, 1979

LinkedIn Profile : https://www.linkedin.com/in/md-golam-murtaja-a709b05